so then my teacher called me to uh his
room he was the Abbott of the monastery
and he called me to his room and he said
you know you're the first uh Foreigner
in 600 years to graduate from our our
Monastery and so congratulations and
they give you a little white scarf
called the Kat they hang it around your
head and then he said uh but you know as
a
foreigner we have a second example
ination for you you know and I'm like
you didn't mention any second
examination then he said oh yeah uh you
go to New York uh you start a business
uh you prove that you understand what we
taught you because they supposedly they
teach you how to shift the future how to
change the future how to shape your
future you know if you understand the
the laws of karma then supposedly you
can adjust your future path and you can
make things happen so they said your
examination is second examination go to
New York start a business make a million
dollars we'll give it away to the
refugees because we're not allowed to
keep money so uh then I fought with him
for like I don't know six months it was
like a silent standoff you're not
supposed to say no to the Llama you
think those rosaries are for uh prayer
you get
this then they will hit you and then you
get these red dots across your
for in the monastery that's where the
rosaries the teachers use the RO that's
why all those Tibetan Monks are so uh
well mannered uh 25 years of
rosaries then uh So eventually I went to
New York and we and I I did start a
business we started with three
people and then now it his reached about
now it's about 250 million a year and
it's it is owned by waren Buffett
um and then people asked me how did you
do that you know people started asking
me how did you do that and then my
friends and I we started giving
trainings uh with different companies
around the world and uh I wrote that
book and the book has been translated
into many languages in countries I don't
know about and additions I don't know
about a lot of them are Black Market but
in Russia and China for example it's
used quite extensively and we've been U
approached by a Russian company they
just got back from Russia uh they have
32,000
employees uh Banking and petroleum and
uh each employee is required to read The
Diamond Cutter uh in Russian and uh I
don't know who's printing it but it's
interesting uh and then uh like that
same in Beijing and China uh so we often
go to China where we're there I don't
know three months a year and we train uh
companies in China about these
principles one day in southern China in
a place called Guang Joo which is where
all the stuff in the world is made
probably the chair you're sitting on uh
outside of Hong Kong and then um I gave
a business talk you know how to use
Diamond Cutter principles uh to be
successful financially and then one lady
raised her hand they go like this right
they don't go like this
you know and she said why shama you know
how do
you can you use this to fix your husband
you know can can you use karmic
principles from Diamond Cutter they call
jingan Jing they have The Diamond Cutter
sura it's the oldest printed book in the
world and can you use those principles
to fix your husband then if some guy of
course raised his hand and said I want
to fix my wife you know and I said yeah
I guess you could I mean they don't
train Us in the monastery for that but
but uh then we started people started
asking and and uh then someone came and
said I have breast cancer can you use
these things can you use these
principles for a serious health problem
then obviously uh many people come and
say I I have enough money and I have a
good relationship and I'm healthy but I
I want peace in my mind I want inner
peace can you use these principles to to
have a peaceful mind and a quiet mind
and you can and then of course
really almost everywhere we go in the
world and we go many many countries uh
in the end someone will ask can you use
these principles for World Peace can you
create uh a world without poverty or
sickness uh is it possible to use these
ancient teachings uh for a world of
peace and uh what's what's interesting
is that if you
learn uh this particular system uh of
life right it's just a way of conducting
your life and it's basically through
ethical principles but in a special way
uh if you learn it uh to achieve your
own goals in life which you can and I
did uh then you can
automatically because of the because of
the nature of this method you are
helping the world also you are creating
a better world and a more peaceful world
and a and a more prosperous world so
just to learn these principles and to
try to put them into practice uh
automatically you are helping to create
a better world it's it's a nice system
by achieving your own goals uh you are
helping the world already and we'll talk
more we have two nights uh to talk about
it and uh I'll get to it by tomorrow
okay by tomorrow evening I I thought uh
so those are the basic goals that people
have in their lives I've been teaching I
don't
know um over 30 years and uh thousands
and thousands tens of thousands of
people and um people basically in their
life they want Financial Security I
don't mean greedy I don't mean you want
three uh cars cuz you only have one
bottom you know
uh or you want a a 20 room house when
you can only sleep in one of those rooms
but people would like to be financially
independent people would like to be able
to buy what they want and have what they
want and do what they want without
thinking about money you see like we
would all like to reach a point in our
finances where we just don't have to
think about money the money comes and we
do the things we want actually most
people in the World when they talk to me
they want to become wealthy they want to
have Financial Independence but in the
end most of them want money because they
want to help other people they want to
uh donate money or they want to help
other causes like the Bill Gates and the
worn buffets of the world uh when you
have enough money when you reach what I
call oxygen money when money is Like
Oxygen for you and you don't have to
think about it uh then you become even
more generous and you start helping
other people so many people I think it's
not a selfish reason they would like to
be financially independent so they could
help more people and then naturally
people would like to have a beautiful
partner it's lonely to have a lot of
money and and to have no friends or to
have no no beautiful partner in your
life and then of course people would
like to have good health I think uh all
of us would like to have energy youthful
energy we would like to be young uh it's
a drag getting old it's a drag getting
tired it's a drag uh to have your mind
uh become more dull as the years go by
and and to know that you were more
creative before and you you can't be as
creative now I mean all of us would like
to be able to affect our our mind and
our energy uh this is basic three
desires of a human life uh in this
system in which I was trained so I was
trained very very strictly for 25 years
and it's a very strict program it's a
very very difficult uh we start at 3:30
in the morning and we go till 10: or 11:
at night and there's no break and a lot
of the the young men go crazy I mean we
lose uh a typical class before you reach
a
gese we you might start with 60 monks
and in the end we had
four uh so it's a very difficult uh
program but if you if you get through it
and if you understand it uh then you can
make stuff happen in your life and it's
like magic so I just go around the world
I don't care I'm not trying to make
people Buddhist it's not my interest uh
I don't care what picture you have in
your house it doesn't matter to me I
still go to All Saints Church I sneak in
there uh on Sunday the early service and
uh down the street and um I don't care I
I don't think uh most of us can relate
to a a blue 12 armed uh God you know
what I mean I and it to me it doesn't
matter uh the principles that I would
like to speak about and then I'm
grateful for Robbie for organizing this
talk uh they are Universal and they are
beautiful and they can and you can
change your life and you can change the
lives of other people so it's just
something learn it uh take away what you
would like uh it it won't work if you
don't try it try it quietly on on your
own you don't have to report back to
anybody and um see if you get $200
million or something you know and and
not because we are greedy people but
because we can help more people and and
I have with the money I have uh 25 years
of uh supporting Tibetan refugees we
just finished uh the last ancient book
from India 4,600 books it took 25 years
we just finished typing in the last book
about a month ago it went up online uh
we cataloged
141,000 texts in St Petersburg Russia in
the Heritage that was finished last year
and we're cataloging all the books in
Mongolia that's 16 years now uh but you
those take money it takes money to do
good things and great things
so here we go all right uh and use it
try to use it okay just try it yourself
quietly try it try it for your own life
it's a way of planting your future it's
a I I have a I live in Rimrock which you
never heard of it's near Camp birie
which you also barely heard
of camp birie for us is the big city
Rimrock is worse uh but I I live on a
Mesa and I I I Garden you know I do
gardening and uh this is the time of
year when I plant you know and I have a
huge box of seeds because all my friends
give me seeds useless seeds from Germany
China Russia things that will never grow
in Arizona so first I throw out all
those and then there's like five boxes
left and then
um I make a drawing of the garden as I
want it to be by June or July and I have
to consider which plants will grow first
and which flowers will open at what time
and who's taller than other ones because
I won't be able to see them from the
porch if I did what I did last year
which was I planted the Z in front of
everything I couldn't see anything
behind them and and you plan your garden
right you can plan your future and your
life in the same way I want to have this
income by next year this time uh I would
like to improve these relationships or I
would like to have this kind of person
in my life by next year this time or six
months from now or I have a bad back and
I would like it to be gone or I would
like my youthful energy back or I would
like my husband to be affectionate again
or things like that you can plant them
according to this ancient wisdom can you
show Diamond
Cutter uh according to this ancient uh
wisdom this is the oldest printed book
in the world with a date on it it's kind
of a bad it's a Google image
okay uh but inside there is this wisdom
and uh I can give you 25 years of it in
two nights okay and then you can start
using it you really you can start using
it okay so we'll just start all right
there are new ideas there are some new
ideas all right and they and you have to
stretch your mind you have to open your
mind and you have to stretch it okay
it's if it's something you heard before
you would have $200
million uh it's something new and then
you have to you have to try and and stay
with me okay so we'll do it the old way
the old uh Tibetan way
thousand years old I'll ask you a
question you have to answer uh what do
you call it
enthusiastically I also have a rosary
here the people in the front row row get
the they get they suffer for the others
okay uh so uh I'll ask you a question
don't be shy and just so here we go what
is this
thing yeah it's depen she she's she's
interested in answering correctly cuz
she's in the front row
uh question if a dog came in here from
the that door if a small puppy dog came
in here and and I and I you know
whistled to it and I said you know and I
waved this thing in front of the puppy
dog what will they
do yeah they would chew on it do they
see this object as a
pen no they don't they see it as
something to chew on right they see it
as a chew toy this sounds like basic
questions but they are important and
they are $200 million questions really
seriously and not just money I mean
relationships that you can have
extraordinary relationships at work and
and in your private life forever if you
understand these things who's right the
dog or the
person I think you can say both and I
think that's a really good answer okay
the dog sees it as a something to choose
chew on the human sees it as a pen it is
validly both a chew toy and a pen there
was only one guy in Florida in all of 30
years who insisted that it was a pen and
uh it couldn't be a Choy and that the
dog was wrong you know and uh I'm sure
the dog thinks we are foolish not to
take advantage of the delicious taste
you know like anyway they're both right
now here comes the important question
okay this is the Deep question and this
is the basis of what I would like to
share with you for two nights okay if I
put this uh object here on this table
and if all the people leave the room and
then if all the dogs leave the
room at that time is it a pen or
something to chew on which
one this is the universal answer every
country they will say
I guess that's Universal I don't know
why but there's some gestures that
aren't Universal I've learned that but
um I was in Brazil and I did some
gesture and that was the wrong one but
uh yeah it's neither one at that time
you can it's not a pen yet until the
human walks back in and it's not a chew
toy until the dog walks in uh left by
itself with no people and no dogs around
at that time it's neither one yet it's
neither one yet it has the what do you
call it it has the potential to be
either one if the human returns or if
the dog returns it will become that if
they both walk back in it will become
both at the same time and there will be
two realities in the in the room uh
parallel realities going on but so long
as there are no observers in the room
then for that long this thing is this
that's the Buddhist uh term is empty
emptiness that's the meaning of
emptiness so I had this thing in uh when
I first got to the monastery you know
I'm this guy I'm like a young hippie
from Phoenix and uh somebody gave me a
photo today of my rock and roll band in
high school I haven't seen it for like
40 years it's pretty funny so that's was
me you know and I go to India you know
and then uh I got to the monastery and I
I said know I I want to study here go I
learned some Tibetan it means I want a
Buddha I want a Buddha and then they
they said okay you can come and then
they gave me this tiny little cell I
Could Touch the walls with my hands you
know and they said you know until you
get to be more senior monk you can stay
here you know so so I I I went in this
tiny room and the beds are all Tibetan
size see Tibetans are all like five feet
tall so I used to sleep with my legs
curled up nowadays they put me in the
penthouse hotel in some in Beijing and
and I still sleep curled up in the in
the corner of this huge bed you know so
uh then I the Llama said okay you do you
understand how to meditate I oh yeah I I
know I know then he said do you know
about emptiness I said I know I know
later he gave me a nickname he he didn't
call me Mike he called me uh Mr I know I
know you know that was my name in the
monastery for like 25 years I know I
know hey I know I know get me a cup of
tea you know so uh so I said okay
meditate about emptiness then I'll ring
the bell and you come up and see me he
had a bell I was like the dog he he had
a
bell uh so he would ring his Bell I
lived with the same llama for 25 years
old cranky old school tobet Lama great
scholar so
I sat down and I meditated about
emptiness and I
thought I closed my eyes and I said
everything is black just black
everything is black black black you know
then I heard the Bell ding ding ding
ding run upstairs then when you come
into a llama's room you have to knock
and they say sh Show means uh come
dog it's the word you use for a dog it's
a sh then you come in and you have to
get down on your knees which I won't do
okay and then you have to slurp I don't
know why you have to to
go it's like respect to show respect to
the llama and interbat and then he said
did you meditate I said yeah what did
you meditate about emptiness what's
emptiness look like I said You Close
Your Eyes everything is black he said
that's emptiness I said yes he said
that's CBA CBA I said what's what's
Koopa mean Lama he says
Idiot you go try again you go try again
then I said don't worry I know I know I
read a book I read a book in America
about emptiness then I went back to my
room close my eyes I watch my thoughts
go through my mind and try not to think
them just watch them they they would
start over near my ear and go over near
my cheek and kind of go out and I would
watch my thoughts go and then not attach
to them and not think about them you
know then I heard the Bell ding ding
ding run up did you meditate yes about
what emptiness what's emptiness close
your eyes don't think about anything if
a thought comes just follow it until it
fades away he said that's emptiness yes
shinda oh what Lama what's a shinda
extremely idiot you know then then I
tried a third time the third time I I
tried to what is that I tried to think
everything when is illusion everything's
an illusion nothing matters don't feel
good don't feel bad just be neutral you
know I thought like that he called me up
I said he says what's emptiness I said
don't feel good don't feel bad don't
think about anything don't feel happy if
someone kisses you don't feel sad if
someone hits you just neutral he said
that's a
shind then I said what's that he says a
super idiot you are a super idiot you
know so then what is emptiness what is
meditation it's
that by itself this is not a pen okay by
it we we you agreed right by the way
this is a trick in tibetan debating we
debate four or five hours a day okay for
25 years so the trick is to L the
opponent oh didn't we
agree uh that if I put the thing here
and the people went out and the dogs
didn't we we all you all nodded at that
point Didn't you and then have to say
yeah cuz you did anybody want to
unod no it's true I mean it is true by
itself it's not a pen or else the dog
would see it as a pen they would pick it
up they would try write a PO to their
dog girlfriend you have a nice tail or
something you see but they don't they
don't have uh they don't see it that way
so why then the big question by the way
this also applies to real estate State
investments in
Manhattan okay the building you saw it's
a 12-story building in Tribeca at the
time we bought it it was a disaster area
and and we made millions and millions of
dollars off that we bought it for $5
million Reagan paid for it and dinkin
the mayor of New York and we didn't pay
electricity and basically free and now
it's Sai and sa is next door and it's
now it's one of the Prime uh areas in
New York so what I'm talking about the
pen applies to real estate and it
applies to business and it applies to
your wife or husband okay so it's not
just a
pen if I see a pen why do I see a pen
and if the dog sees something to chew on
why because if we can answer that we
could make a real estate investment
right and make a lot of money you
see why do I see a pen you see and the
answer according to ancient wisdom is
that there's a seed in my mind I have a
seed in my mind and and then that seed
opens when when gashi
Michael goes like this slow motion right
slow mo GUI Michael goes like this and
he says what is
this and then you see a pen right
according to this
thinking there's a seed in your mind for
a pen and that seed as I as I extend my
hand in the same instant that seed opens
in your own mind and and actually a
picture of a seed a small picture of a
seed comes out of that sorry a pen a
small picture of a pen comes out of your
mind and and your mind puts it on this
subject and the dog has a different seat
in their mind and and a different
picture arises in their thoughts and a
different picture comes out and a
picture of a good real estate investment
in a bad bad area of New York Tribeca
was the worst area in New York now it's
the meat packing District right it's hot
it's really hot now the real estate is
crazy how do you see opportunities like
that how do you know something's going
to happen right how do you know that a
certain area is going to be worth 10
times more in five years how do you know
those things if you have a seed in your
mind you can know those things and if
you don't then you'll probably chew on
it okay no I'm I'm not kidding okay
everything according to ancient Tibetan
idea is coming from your own mind but
not randomly there's a you can control
the process okay is this a real
pen yes or no don't is it yeah it's real
I have this joke I say anybody thinks
it's not real come up here I'll give you
a mustache you know like I can you can
have a Hitler mustache or Saddam Hussein
must anyone you want you know like you
know of course it's real is it coming
from your mind yes if it wasn't coming
from your mind then the dog would see a
pen get it you must get that okay and
it's true it's true it is coming from
your mind if it's not coming from your
mind then the dog would see a pen so in
the monaster somebody will say it's
coming from my mind but it's still real
I can still write with it and the and
they get a
rosary from the Llama just they say the
last word comes out of their mind out of
their mouth they say it's it's coming
from my mind but it's still
real then they say what's wrong what did
I say wrong you know Lama will
say it's not real even though it comes
from your mind it's real because it
comes from your
mind like say it right say it correctly
it's not real even though it comes from
your mind it's real because it comes
from your mind and nothing that didn't
come from your mind could be
real okay there's nothing in the world
that doesn't come from your mind which
is real okay everything that's real that
works real estate investment real uh
real estate
Investments they also come from your
mind and that's what makes them real and
you can control them and then you can
you can have a comfortable life material
life you can donate money to many causes
you can help help many
people then the question is very simple
but by the way we will take a break okay
but I got to get the basic stuff in
before the break in case somebody runs
away
um the big question then is simple
simply becomes how do I plant a seed you
see how do I plant a seed how how is a
seed planted in the mind because then I
could
Garden the next six months of my life I
could purpose plant seeds for financial
Independence I could make my husband
more affectionate I could return my
wife's interest in intimacy I could uh
fix my bad back I could make my
household more peaceful and my own mind
your thoughts also are arising from
seeds in your mind your own thoughts are
also coming from seeds and you can
change the capacity of your mind okay
you can change you can learn foreign
languages you can play upright base
after never playing it in your whole
life just pick it up and play it you see
you can do cool stuff if you know how to
plant seeds so here's how you plant a
seed
okay okay Scotty it's time for some
money you have any money this is how I
make extra money I borrow money from
him I always forgot to give it back
nothing yeah my mind is not creating
okay I'll take the example of money it's
not because I'm concerned with money I
don't care about money much I didn't go
live in a monastery for 25 years because
I wanted to make
money uh I went there cuz my mother died
my mother died very badly and I left
school I was in Princeton I left I
walked out and I I went to India because
I wanted to know why you know then I the
dama May forced me to finish my degree
but uh but money is a good example you
see why money is uh measurable you see
if I told you I'm 200 million times
happier than I was last year you can't
prove it I can't prove it uh but if I
say I have $200 million company then you
can look it up online and you can check
it so money is good for example just for
an example okay I'm not trying
to make you all greedy or something okay
it would be nice right to have enough
money as much money as you want and you
never have to think about it okay
somebody else does the accounts right
where is she in those two in the
back in the
corner they probably want to show me
books or something nah okay
uh how do you plant a seed for some
money you see
uh then according to the system that
thing which you want to plant a seed for
you must give it to another person that
you must give it to another person and
there is no other way to plant a seed
and according to these ideas there is no
other way to make money not possible the
only way every penny of the world's
economy has been generated by generosity
uh all
money is is a all money is a is a mental
impression and that impression can only
be planted by by serving another person
with money you see so it's a very
beautiful idea and it's and it works
okay then people automatically you're
sitting there I can see your mind we are
trained right for 25 years to see the
other guys in mind right I can see your
mind oh my mother was very generous and
she just got more and more broke every
year they went by she gave more money
and then she got more and more broke and
she died broke right you will think
things like that you know generous
people who didn't make $200 million and
weren't Buffet bought their company
right you know that and then I say they
didn't know the technique they didn't
know how to plant the seed they planted
some seeds but they was like taking uh
watermelon seeds and throwing them on
the floor concrete floor they did the
right thing but they didn't know how to
do it you see and they didn't plant it
properly uh people are kind people are
giving people are generous but they
don't know how to how to make that seed
grow in the right place inside the mine
okay if you learn that you can have
everything you can have whatever you
want it's very
beautiful so the technique is actually
kindness right it's cool isn't that nice
that the way to get rich is to be kind
with with uh
technique I teach a lot in South
America in Russia it's
aik right it's always in every country
it's a fanga in
Chinese uh you have to know the
technique so for these two nights my job
is to teach you technique how to be kind
uh how to how to be kind and plant a
seed and then the things you want you
can have okay I often think uh of uh the
person I have a long spiel I do I'm not
going to do it okay I'm going to save
you the
trouble but I think about the guy who
invented uh farming right and they were
hunter gatherers before that they went
out in the forest they tried to find
some wild berries they tried to find
rice sometimes they did sometimes they
didn't when they didn't find rice for
enough days the family died and that was
the way it was you wandered around the
forest and if you got lucky you lived
for another week you see what I mean
that was the old way what do we do now
take some
seeds dig in the ground put the seeds
there cover it with technique fertilize
it properly correct watering not too
much not too little all at the same
correct time know the technique of
farming and you will have rice next year
that's how
and because of the invention of farming
civilizations can rise people have time
to read books and write books and write
music and Jazz
and and and have a city you can't have a
city of of GA gatherers hunter gatherers
cannot make cities okay in our stage of
evolution in this world everybody in
this world almost everybody is a hunter
gatherer they are wandering around
Phoenix looking for money you know
hoping to find some you know or a
partner or a yoga class that can make
them young you see people are wandering
around Phoenix looking hoping you know
and and according to a a
really a diamond color State of Mind
these people are all crazy they're all
like cavemen
they are just like cavemen and then
there're they're stunned person say what
what' you do today I went looking for a
job why I need
money why didn't you just plant
some I don't know how you see we are
like that you see imagine if I know how
suppose I know how to plant money
imagine how frustrating it is to watch
people suffer their whole life looking
for money out forest and if they don't
get it they die right so here's how you
plant it just learn to plant it and I
truly believe that it will change the
future of of our world I believe it's
another step in Civilization I believe
that 50 years from now if our work
succeeds people will just plant what
they
need where tell me where in other people
okay uh this system is like an echo or a
basketball okay you can't make an echo
without a wall you cannot bounce a
basketball without a floor you cannot
plant a mental seed without another
person who is in need it's not possible
cannot be done okay so the first job in
this system is I have to find someone
who wants some
money you see it sounds crazy right I
want to make money well what are you
going to do well of course I have to
find someone who wants money and then
help them make money you see it also
makes you extremely
popular
I have $200 million and give it away
everybody's like smiles when you walk in
the room
uh the system is that you need someone
else who need who wants some money okay
you need can I try do you mind I'll give
you some his money I don't care uh so I
want to plant a seed in my mind for
money in the future okay do you get a
watermelon five minutes after you plant
a seed no there's a maturation process
okay same with the mental seeds don't
think you're going to give her 10 and
get a 100 before you leave the room it's
possible but you have to be a really
good
farmer okay in the beginning it will
take a couple weeks or something okay so
uh I want I want $100 in my life and I'm
not greedy I wanted to help more
refugees I want more money to help more
refugees okay so then I must give I must
plant the seed I reach out she reaches
out her hand now watch I gotta it's got
to be higher okay one two three it makes
contact with her hand close I let go
then the seed is planted in my mind okay
how how did it get into my mind I saw
myself give through my eyes my eyes are
like a what do you call a lens of a
camera and my mind saw my hand and my
hand let go and in that moment that my
hand that my hand lets go and my mind
sees my hand let go I plant a seed
that's all okay you cannot use this
system without other people not possible
and they must be in need and you must
provide what they need okay
good
okay don't let him take it back no you
got more no it's
okay
uh then there's technique okay there's
technique involved you know many people
who are generous uh they did not make a
millions of dollars okay and that's just
the true so after the break I suggest
after the break when you are well
restored uh let's start talking about
technique okay we'll start tonight and
we'll continue into tomorrow there's a
technique from ancient times Diamond
Jing Jing Diamond cutor Sutra uh which
you must learn okay and if you
understand that technique you can make
changes in your spouse you can make
changes in your health uh you can change
your financial situation okay just in
case someone
leaves I'll ask you a question question
is this a selfish thing to
do to give money because you want
it I think not because
uh it's a win-win it's a win-win is she
upset that I'm using her to make money
no she just made 10 bucks uh am I happy
that she let me give her the money yes I
will make a 100 if I know what I'm doing
100 will come okay is that a selfish
thing I don't think so
especially if it's part of my
intention when I help you that I should
be
successful and people will copy me
people will imitate me they will say how
did you make 200 mil I say just give con
techn with technique
give with technique then people unless
you're insane you will try it you some
guy standing up there you can check
online he did a certain thing oh then
I'm going to try it okay he he looks
like he did
it it it makes sense it's even sign of
there's a deep logic to it then there's
a compassion to it I like it this is
success with compassion you know I like
it if it's true then this is the way the
world should run and everyone would copy
me and then there would be no poverty in
the world World half the people would be
getting the
$10 half the people would be farming the
$10
$100 you see what I mean if
this if this system is
true it would remove poverty from the
world okay simply that and that's not
selfish that's love that's compassion
okay all right uh we'll take a break uh
my suggestion is don't change your whole
life in one night right we in our
tradition you should change very slowly
and you should do a practical experiment
you should choose and in fact the first
uh step to the seed planting technique
on the small piece of paper is to decide
what you what's your experiment going to
be okay choose an experiment in your
life 25% of your company right some part
of your life choose something that you
would like to to some goal in your life
or something it could be Financial you
know I want to I want to pay off my
credit cards in three months or
something or it could be I want to make
$60,000 in the next two months or
something you decide set a goal uh or it
could be your relationship I want the
most one of the most difficult karmas of
all to create is uh to get your husband
to wash the dishes regularly so you know
you could set that as a
goal uh it could be physical well I have
some physical problem or like that it
could be mental I have I get depressed
sometimes or or I feel a lack of
motivation sometimes like that choose
something 25% of your factory that you
want to work on tonight okay CU
otherwise you're wasting your time and
I'm wasting my time okay you choose
something don't don't change your whole
Mafia Factory in one night like choose a
little part of your life and say okay
this guy you let's try it you know I'll
make a small investment in your system I
will I will make one goal I will state
in one simple sentence what I would like
to achieve in the next three months or
something like that set a goal okay
otherwise there's no reason to come here
there's no reason for me to talk Robbie
do all this work Bonnie do all this work
Mercedes all these people you know paid
for things and it took a lot of work to
to pull this event off for us to get a
free night is extremely rare so let's
use the time you decide something you
want in your life okay anything anything
you want but choose something okay
that's step number one you have to you
have to choose something I I'll give you
a question funny
question If a person comes to me and
says I don't know what I want
what should I tell
them what's the way to plant the seed to
know what you
want yeah help someone else figure out
what they want to do with their life but
we did we're ahead of ourselves okay but
if you don't know what to put down for
number one help somebody else put
something down and it will come okay so
step number one decide what you want
right now I'm going to do something very
rare which to shut up for one
minute let's see if I can really do it
okay they have a clock I'll shut up for
one minute honestly really from my heart
please think of something you'd like to
to have in your life anything doesn't
matter okay up to you you don't have to
tell
anybody I'll I'll try
also okay
you okay everybody have something try if
if the mafia guy in KF can try it you
can try you can make some small
investment of your time okay uh so
that's number one please don't forget
tonight and tomorrow keep that in mind
okay keep that in mind okay second step
on your refrigerator
card
uh you must
identify another person in your life who
wants the thing same thing or something
similar okay it doesn't have to be
exactly the same thing some guy told me
I I want all the vanilla ice cream I can
get can I can I give my my friend wants
chocolate chip will I still create the
right seeds I said yeah there's a little
bit of leeway
here
okay so yeah someone who wants something
similar to you but pretty much the same
okay now I'll tell you an almost
Universal reaction in every continent of
the
world I don't know anybody who wants
that you know people come to me then I I
say you look for 24 hours through your
family through your friends through your
co-workers to your neighbors look for
someone who might want something similar
to what you want get back to me email me
then they always find 10 okay they
always find 10 which proves that we just
don't pay attention to what other people
need okay it just proves who we are you
see I don't know anybody who's having
trouble with their husband check you
know get back to me in 24 hours then
they're like everybody's having trou
with their husband I said good you have
more material to work with you know okay
so uh find someone who wants the same
thing that you want part of the Second
Step By the way in in tibetan these are
called she say she she s j
t the four together are called leam
those are the four words in tibetan
second one is SAA SAA means find a
person who almost wants the same thing
and make a plan to help them okay make a
plan to help help them
now the help does not have to be
professional okay I'll tell you why Okay
g I decided what I want step number one
what do you want step number one I want
to be Financial independent and right
now I'm deep in credit card debt you
know then I said okay what's step number
two choose a person who has the same
problem okay find someone else who has
credit card problems they're not hard to
find okay then what's the second half
number two I have to make a plan to help
them okay take them out to a Starbucks I
always I even call them the four
Starbucks steps I think sometimes
uh you know take them to a Starbucks and
talk to them and help them that's step
number three by the way step number
three is uh go to the Starbucks go to
the Starbucks okay step number two is
identify a person who needs the same
thing and make a plan okay which
Starbucks will you take them to at what
time and on what street I think it's
Scottdale and Fifth Street or something
right there's a little Starbucks there
oh there's one higher up yeah I know
where they are
uh but you should ask me a question okay
I'm by the way usually I don't give you
questions till the second day because
you don't know enough to ask a good
one but we'll see we'll see if we have a
little extra time we have about half an
hour if I can
finish think of think I'll tell you what
tonight think of some tough questions
for me for tomorrow okay maybe tomorrow
we in the middle we'll do some tough
questions give me some good questions
tough questions in the tobet we like
tough questions you know
[Music]
yeah like that then you knock the guy's
head but I won't do that
um but you should ask me you should ask
me you want me who's a financial
incompetent to take out someone else
who's having financial trouble and give
them advice you know is that step number
three
yes uh but it's fortunate that intention
is
90% of seed planting okay all you have
to do is want to help them and take a
good shot at it and that's enough the
desire to not ignore other people's
problems the desire to help them with
their problems is enough to plant a seed
for your own Financial Independence you
don't have to be a financial expert
because you're not or you wouldn't have
to be doing this got it okay it's the
desire to help which is Paramount and
that's 90% of the power of the seed so
make a plan
it must be concrete it must be specific
it cannot be vague then the seed will be
vague and you will get vague
results discovery card will offer you a
card
okay it happened to me I know it feels
really bad um
okay uh to plant a seed properly it must
be extremely intentional and extremely
clear in your mind there must be a clear
plan I will take them out and it has to
be regular I will take them out every
Friday uh Starbucks on Scottdale and
whatever the crossroad is and I will
give them 45 minutes of my time and not
less I will give them 45 minutes of my
time and I will try to help them I will
support them in in their financial
problems okay that's all in this system
is if you don't do that you cannot
succeed oh no Gesa I had some success
earlier in my
life that was an accident okay really
you didn't have any control of it it
came to you because of something you had
done earlier some kindness you had
rendered earlier and you had some
success and then it went away because
you didn't know where it was coming from
you see what I mean it
it's the story of so many successful
people musicians business people
anything actors you know I can't I have
a a person in our group who's an Academy
Award nominee I won't say their name but
they can't get a job they can't get any
acting jobs they and they didn't know
why they didn't uh know why what
happened what
changed you were living off an old debit
card and it ran out and you didn't know
where it came from okay I have a lot of
actors now in my uh I teach a lot of
actors this system what do you think is
the way to get an acting
part yeah when the auditions come you
try to find three other people who might
want to audition against you and you
help them and you support them and you
try to pitch them to the director of the
film okay well who was that I can say
her name summer more she's a lady in La
she tried my system she just got a
multifilm part a leading role she just
did it this way she helped other people
get roles you see what I mean with
technique which I'm teaching you right
four steps right so third third part
take them to Starbucks it must be
regular you don't plant a seed in a day
it I would say once a week try once a
week okay to fix your finances make a
regular date with someone who's
struggling and give them support and
help once a week regularly okay same
time each week what you want you must
offer to others regularly or it won't
work doing it once is not going to make
anything happen it's like throwing a a
watermelon seed uh on the on concrete
okay it's not enough it has to become a
way of life that you help others it has
to to become part of your way of life
your regular way of life okay it has to
become an instinct that when you want
something you try to get it for someone
else it must become instinctual and
right now we have the opposite Instinct
what I want I must take from others I
must deny to others I must compete with
others that's that's our current
Instinct you see and to change an
instinct is very very hard okay so it
has to be regular it has to become
instinctual oh my husband yelled at me I
have to stop yelling at the
kids instead of getting angry at the
husband your automatic instinct is to
who am I yelling at why how should I
stop my yelling with someone else you
see what I mean like that it must become
an instinct if enough people change that
instinct this world will change the
whole world will change people will act
differently towards each other those who
don't want to be yelled at will stop
yelling in order to not be yelled
at and it will just be an instinct and
the world will change okay okay step
number four uh I think that most
generous people in the world who didn't
become financially
successful because of their
generosity could have been if they had
done number four okay number four is the
most important one step number four is
the most important one what's it say
there I forget what it says what does it
say yeah okay let's talk about coffee
[Music]
meditation Scotty you are you available
no you are you're not running anything
okay come up here and sit in a chair I
have a skit okay that I do and I don't
want you not to see it even though it's
it's going to take five minutes or
something you have to sit
here okay so I lived uh with this the D
Lama sent me to uh I was in uh India I
was studying at his place and then my
mom got very ill and then he said uh I
said well what should I do he said you
should go home to Phoenix you should
take care of your mother you know to
serve her you know then I'm like well is
there any llamas in America that I could
go work with with while I'm there and he
said yeah there's one you know then I
said where where does he live and he
said he said the worst thing that the
dial could say to
anybody New
Jersey you know I'm like what New Jersey
he lives in New Jersey I'm like the
armpit of the nation you know and he's
like yeah yeah you have to go to New
Jersey so you know I went to New Jersey
I studied with this llama for a while
he's going to be the Llama okay then uh
at some point I was working in New York
in the diamond business it's a from our
you have to come back to the monastery
every night it was a small Mongolian
Monastery in New Jersey
and in a town of Mongolians that's
another story but uh you have to come
back every night it's two hours on the
bus and the subway in it's two hours
back four hours of communing a day so I
would go into New York come back I'd be
exhausted I walk in exhausted to the
monastery
and then uh I would hear the Llama
upstairs you know and he's uh he's
watching television okay so in the
monastery the big llamas can watch
television but not the little monks so I
was a little monk you know so the little
monks are always trying to figure out
what how to get up to the llama's room
for like a half
hour so you know I'm like God I really
like to watch some he used to watch New
York Matts you
know he I don't know he decided he loved
baseball anybody know baseball anybody
know Daryl strawberry
playoffs last hit of the game it's a
line
drive and it goes like
this and drops over the wall that was my
llama he was like he was he was oh money
me home money baby I said Rim that's
cheating oh money baby money
baby you got to see the footage you can
see it on YouTube look up Daryl
strawberry 196 okay it wasn't the World
Series it was the playoffs uh the World
Series was mooki Wilson and hit between
the Pittsburgh guys legs anyway that's
another story Bill Buckner I'm not
kidding these are all voodoo from my
teacher uh so so anyway I'm like I'd
really like to go up there and watch
television so you make a him a cup of
tea Tibetan tea salt butter cream half
and half milk
nutmeg and then you have to swoosh it in
a churn uh in a big Butter Churn like a
wooden thing you know it's a big deal
and they drink 25 cups a
day and then uh so I made him a cup you
know take it up then you have to knock
on the door you know took then he say
sh
sh you dog then uh you come in and he'd
be watching you got to do the he's
watching television you know then you
come in and say llama you have to serve
the tea like this you know and you say I
have your tea for you give him the tea
and then he's watching the Mets and then
you have to go like
this you know and then you're like
watching the map you know and then you
think he's not he doesn't notice that
you're there you know but llamas Have
Eyes in the back you know and he'd say
he'd say what are you doing I say oh
Lama just let me sit here I've been four
hours on the bus today you know I just
want to watch some just I want to what
do you call that fry my brain for half
an hour you know not think about
anything then he said okay you can what
do you call it
zone out yeah I want to zone
out I lost a lot of English in 25 years
okay so uh so I just want to zone out
llama you know and then he'd say did you
do your meditation today and I'd say
like no mama was on the bus for four
hours how am I going to do my meditation
today you have to do your
meditation then I'm like all right I'll
go do my meditation then he say sit on
the couch then he had this couch it some
wealthy person gave him a couch it's a
like teak wood and gold thread real gold
thread only one person ever sat on this
couch the Dal Lama when he came to visit
our house he sat on the couch right so
he's like sit on the couch then
sometimes the Llama asks you to do
something wrong so they can hit you
so I'm like that's okay R I'm really
comfortable right here sit on the couch
he really liked dirty hairy and he
started to talk like dirty hariry uh no
when he learned English it was I'll sit
on the couch then I if they have to ask
you three times they hit you anyway so
I'm like okay okay I'll sit on the couch
you know and I sit on the couch lie down
on the couch
then in Tibet your feet are uh profane
your feet are uh very filthy you know
it's like when Jesus before uh when was
that Thursday before Easter coming up he
washed his disciples feet also in in the
judaic tradition the in ancient times
the feet were very unclean so in Tibet
you're never supposed to put your feet
up on anything and you can't Point them
at anybody put your feet up on the couch
on the gold thread couch yes put them up
there but I thought you wanted me to
meditate we are meditating shut up lie
down they say katum say katum katum
katum means shut your mouth you know
it's funny every time I teach people bad
words they remember them right away and
I teach him some holy sacred thing and
they can't remember anyway so he says
katum see down then lie down on the
couch then he said now prop up your head
then he sent the other monk he had
another servant monk named Jamba said
get Mike some coffee go get Mike some
coffee then he he run down come back
with some coffee drink the coffee
yes think about number three and number
two what think about number three didn't
you go to Starbucks today with anybody I
did I did think about it think about the
plan you made why that makes the seed
work okay that makes the seed work and
why your mother didn't get rich she
didn't know about number four which is
coffee meditation okay so you you have
to clarify the karma you have to sharpen
it you have to define it you have to
increase the resolution of the karma and
that can only be done by appreciating
yourself and what you are doing the good
things you are doing when
we when we go to bed when we lay down on
the pillow we start to worry because
we're tired okay in the morning you
don't have those worries right only in
the dark at the end of the day never in
the sunlight of the morning can you have
have those worries but as you sleep as
you go to sleep because you're tired and
it's dark then worries start to come up
in your mind oh oh you know my boss
doesn't like me maybe I can't keep my
job I have all these debts you know like
my husband is blah blah blah and you
start to have
unreasonable worries start to get
exaggerated as you fall
asleep in this system okay you can
retire
because I can't stay like that that's so
long uh in this
system you you are required it will not
work unless you do coffee meditation as
you fall asleep you must struggle
against your mind your mind will go to
bad places sad places oh I I not have
enough money or my so and so doesn't
like me my husband said that and you you
grab your mind like a strong hand you
grab your mind and you say we are not
thinking those things tonight we are
thinking good thoughts tonight about
what we did today that was good and you
fight with your mind and you say come
over here and you think about the good
things you did today did you take
someone to Starbucks did you try to help
somebody with their credit card debt
even though you are submerged in your
own credit card debt did you at least
try then you say yes what did it look
like they sat across the table on the
right side which chair the first of the
two on the left what did they order
coffee with a little bit of cream no
sugar what did you say to them I said
maybe we can help each other with our
financial problems talk to me let's talk
to each other what did you say next
relive The Experience like a what do you
call in the
football instant yeah instant replaying
yeah do some instant replays of the time
you spent with another person serving
them and your mind
will my husband doesn't like me I have
financial problems come back come back
come back come back think about good
things you did to do oh and my friend
said something to me no sh shut up katum
come back now you're going to remember
katum think about good things that
struggle to force your mind to come back
back to something pleasant as you are
falling asleep that exercise of grasping
your own mind in your hand in your
mental hand and forcing it to think
about something positive what's the name
of
that it's meditation that is meditation
and that's the meaning of meditation it
isn't close your eyes and think about
nothing it's to force the mind to go
where you want you are going to think
about good things tonight you are going
to think about the good things we did
that's step four that clarifies the
karmic stene in your mind it sharpens it
it won't take sick lifetimes to ripen
okay seriously okay think about it as
you fall asleep the kind things you have
done there is no expiration
date good news okay if you didn't do it
a single good thing today you can think
about something good you did yesterday
or 10 years ago go okay I'm not kidding
I'm not kidding and there's another
thing in in the system in the debate
ground that they teach us if you can't
think of something that you've done then
appreciate what someone else is doing
okay some kindness you have observed
another person doing you get
10% it's the numbers there in the
scripture I didn't make it up okay you
get 10% Okay so and they don't lose
anything got it it's an extra 10% okay
it's not like they they Dro to 90 okay
it's not like that okay but that's
meditation that's the meaning of
meditation is to is to compel the mind
to think about what you wanted to think
about and it's difficult and that's
meditation and that that hand which
grasps the mind and puts it over onto
what a good thing to think about before
you sleep that muscle will increase that
muscle will get stronger and that's
meditation and in in a few weeks you you
lay back on your bed and automatically
the kindnesses you have done today will
come to your mind okay and it's very
beautiful the word INB betan for
meditation is G say
g g means to do something over and over
again until it becomes natural to you
and that's the word for meditation in
Tibet
Force the mind as you fall asleep to
think about something good you've done
today and in time it will become a habit
and every time you lay your head down
you will think of the kindnesses you
have done to others okay then you fall
asleep on that in your
subconscious every 24 hours a seed
planted that way doubles in its power
how does an untrained person who never
saw the inside of a business at all make
a $200 million company in the fastest in
New York history
how coffee
meditation okay it's step number four
okay you don't have to know anything you
just have to know coffee okay step
number four before as you fall asleep
think of the good things you've done my
we got a call one day at the monastery
in New
Jersey and uh they said this is the
Catholic church in Lakewood Lakewood
area uh New Jersey and it's a very
beautiful church it's a what do you call
Cathedral and they said uh the pope has
issued a what do they call that when the
pope issues a an encyclical the pope has
ised an cyclical that all Catholic
churches are required to invite other
religions priests and monks to come and
talk about their faith so would you
would your Lama come
and talk about Buddhism in the church so
you know I asked him and he said sure I
I I'll do it you know so I was his
driver and his cook and his Gardener and
his clothes washer and sometimes his
translator and so I got to go with him
you know and it was beautiful it was
stunning we were walking down the middle
of this beautiful stone Cathedral you
know and he was like so happy you know
he's like wow what are those guys in
those windows colored Windows look the
sun is coloring the the guys you know
and the priest was like oh those are
Saints you know wow that's such a good
idea then he's like take a note Mike we
got to have those colored windows in our
Temple I'm like okay I got it you know
and then and then he's looking and then
halfway down the cathedral he he stops
and he there's this little room off to
the side and a priest is coming in one
side and then this lady is coming in the
other side through a different door and
he's like grabbing the priest he's like
what you know what's going on in there
what are they doing in there he said
don't worry don't worry it's a special
custom what are they doing in there the
priest goes in the lady goes in and then
the lady tells the priest all the bad
stuff she did last
week oh well then what did they do well
then he tells her to do some prayers on
these beads oh he's like like a mantra
likey yeah yeah Hail Mary oh money Hail
Mary over and over you know and then all
the bad karma is gone you know and he
says that's perfect that's exactly what
we do you know he says that's a
purification chamber you know and he
says I understand I uh it's a great
custom you guys have you know your
church is all right you know and then
he's then he goes my llama goes like
this where's the other one and the
priest goes what other one he says you
know the other room on the left side and
the priest says what what do you mean
the other one he says you know where the
lady comes and the priest comes in and
and the lady tells the priest all the
good stuff she did last
week and and the priest is like you
could see he's like getting an idea you
know like yeah maybe we need one of
those a rejoicing chamber you know like
so in this tradition in the Tibetan
tradition uh we are
required to do step number four coffee
meditation means when you come
home you know change your clothes have
dinner wash the
dishes you can watch TV for half an hour
okay as long as you're supporting the
right team and then
uh change you know take your bath and
then put on your nightclothes lay down
down on your bed and you must fall
asleep thinking about kind things you
have done for other people or this
system will not work for you okay it
will not work okay you have to do that
step number four is is is essential it
doesn't work without step number four
okay and it's a beautiful custom It's a
Wonderful custom to go to sleep that way
you sleep well you never have trouble
sleeping cuz your mind
as you fall asleep you're thinking sweet
thoughts about kind things you've done
and the whole night your mind is happy
and contented and you wake up with a
bright happy mind you see it's a very
power we could put all those drug
companies out of business you know it's
a very wonderful way to fall asleep okay
so you must do step number four okay
those are so those are the
four steps to planting a seed in your
mind number one decide what you want
number two find someone else who needs
it and make a plan for a Starbucks why
do I say
Starbucks I like neutral spaces if
you're going to help somebody don't
invite them to your house and don't go
to their house a Starbucks is a neutral
place for everybody everybody can go to
Starbucks it's comfortable for everybody
I gave this long talk in Bueno staris uh
actually for some government some of the
government is using this in argen Ina
I'm not allowed to say
who but uh one guy in the audience he
came up and thanked me afterwards he had
a very nice suit on and and I'm like
shake his hand he says I want to thank
you I said well you're welcome and he I
said what do you do he says I'm the
manager of all the Starbucks in
Argentina he says do you have stock in
Starbucks I said not yet you know but uh
so uh find a new neutral space okay it
doesn't have to be Starbucks I guess it
could be McDonald's that's a little
harder but find a neutral space and and
take them there okay and make a real
plan and that plant your karmas like
that we have
about I think Robbie or or Bonnie's
goingon to make a talk
after uh maybe one or two questions if
you if you have any yet I don't know and
and don't be shy okay we are trained to
be
attacked and I am often attacked as you
may find out and I'm happy so go for it
what if the
person yeah it's a good question
um I will give two examples and I'll
repeat her question she said what if the
person that you've chosen to help
doesn't really want to help I I will
give two examples uh one if I have a
problem with anger
who should I take to
Starbucks don't be British yeah someone
else sorry if there's any britishers in
here oh there where is that yeah sorry
Esther don't take it personally you're
in Arizona now uh yeah you should find
the angriest person you could find but
you don't go to them and say you know
what out of all the people I know you're
the angriest
person so my suggestion in that case
and this works very sweetly you you go
to them and you say look I've just
realized I have a problem with anger and
I wondered if we could just work
together I wondered if you could help me
because you what you do is you you put
it this way you aim it this way I have a
financial problem I have I'm underwater
with my credit cards I don't need a
financial expert I just need a friend
who can talk with me once a week would
you be willing to talk with me once a
week like that so you
can that's how I would approach the
angry person otherwise they might punch
you so do that also in this tradition we
are not allowed to uh Force our opinions
on other people I'm not allowed to bang
on your door grab you by the collar and
say do you accept the four Starbucks
steps you know and uh we're actually not
allowed
to uh we're actually not allowed to push
these ideas on other people if they want
to know if they're happy to learn we're
we're encouraged to share and if it
seems like they don't want to learn
we're encouraged to leave them alone and
and you know just pray that they have a
good life and they're happy and but
we're not allowed to like what do you
call that um prati we're not allowed to
prosze but another answer to your
question if I have a problem in my life
that the people I offer help are not
willing to accept that help which would
make me happy to give what should I
do no or I should be more willing to
accept Health you see and then my seeds
will change and then the people I meet
will be more willing to accept my help
because giving help is a pleasure and
it's a high pleasure it's the highest
pleasure in life to be denied that
pleasure is a very sad thing so if
people in your life are denying you the
pleasure of helping them it may be that
you are refusing the gifts of others and
then you have to be more willing to let
someone give you a gift you know what I
mean and then your seeds will change and
then suddenly you'll you'll meet people
who who are dying to have your help
because giving help is a pleasant
occupation in live right okay works
we'll do more questions tomorrow okay
and thank you for coming try to imagine
uh
someone who believes he has learned to
plant anything he wants in his life and
he wants to share it he wants other
people like the First Farmer is trying
to talk the second farmer into not
eating all the rice but bury some
underground and the second farmer is
like you're crazy man and you now give
some give some money to get money give
some of what you have to to get and it
will come okay it will always come and
you can't stop it okay all right did you
have some announcement
yeah
e
e e